WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.MY-SUBS.com --
Summon the legions. It is time.
Our enemy vows to attack.
Who among you will stand and fight?
You will die.
Long have I awaited this day.
I pledge my loyalty to Sauron.
Half of us just left.
But half stayed.
Why wasn't I chosen for the expedition?
Thought you were going west.
Not till I've done
something worthy of Númenor.
I have just convinced
Númenor to send five ships
and 500 men to aid your people
and place a crown upon your head.
You are asking me to go to the one
place that I swore never to return.
Why do you keep fighting?
Because I cannot stop.
Come with me, and together we
will redeem both our bloodlines.
We head nor'-east.
For Middle-earth.
It is no sword. It is a power.
Have you heard of Sauron?
I've seen this before.
It is a key.
The enemy commander spoke of giving
the Orcs a home in these lands.
Whatever his design,
this much is certain.
Our enemy knows your son has
what he needs to enact it.
How long?
Maybe hours.
New life.
In defiance of death.
My children,
we have endured much.
We cast off our shackles.
Crossed mountain, field,
frost, and fallow
till our feet bloodied the dirt.
From Ered Mithrin to the Ephel Arnen,
we have endured.
Yet tonight, one more trial awaits us.
Our enemy may be weak,
their numbers meager...
...yet before this night is
through, some of us will fall.
But for the first time, you do so
not as unnamed slaves in far-away lands,
but as brothers.
As brothers and sisters in our home!
Nampat.
Nampat! Nampat!
This is the night
- we reach out the iron hand of the Uruk...
- Nampat! Nampat!
...and close our fist
around these lands.
Nampat!
Search it.
All of you! Fan out! Find them!
Meaning no offense,
Lord-father, but where is he?
What happened to Sauron?
Can't find tooth nor tail of him.
Must've got smart and scarpered.
No. The Elf's here.
I smell him.
Yes, Father.
Up here!
Bring him down!
Get out, now!
Open that door!
Get out!
Lord-father! You must move now!
You must move!
How many of 'em could
have survived that?
How long do we have?
Not long enough.
Come on, we have to
make ready the village.
Easy, Berek. Easy, boy.
Hoist it up!
I thought all soldiers were to be abed.
Pardon me, Commander. I... I was only...
Hoping to get the first sight of land?
At ease.
It'll be visible to your
eyes in a few moments.
Is it visible to yours already?
Has been for nearly an hour.
Keen are the eyes of the Elves.
And yet, mine have not before seen you.
Swinging steel nor flying sail.
What is your rank?
Stable sweep.
Despise not the labor
which humbles the heart.
Humility has saved entire kingdoms
the proud have all but led to ruin.
I did not join this expedition
to be humbled, Commander.
Then for what did you join, soldier?
I was just trying to get away.
As far as I could from that place.
Númenor?
It's not Númenor.
Not the real Númenor, anyway.
If it ever existed.
It existed.
It exists still...
If only in the heart of
the lowliest stable sweep.
It's Isildur.
I might have known.
You have the look of your father.
I was always told I
look more like my mother.
Soldier.
Captain.
His mother...
What happened to her?
It is strange.
Most of my life, I've looked east
to see the Sun rise over the sea.
And west to see it set over the land.
We're sailing into the
dawn, and yet, to me,
it feels like the coming of night.
She drowned.
Land has been sighted, Your Majesty.
How long before we make anchor?
It's a full day's sail into the mountains.
And from there, another
day's ride east into the vale.
Signal the other ships.
Tell them to make all possible haste.
It is beyond our skill to destroy.
Where will you hide it?
No one must know.
Not even you.
Our enemy has been sighted.
We survived them before.
Now we must do so again.
Tonight.
Our position gives us an advantage.
But to use it, we must
draw the enemy in close.
We must wait until every last Orc
has crossed that bridge
to spring our attack.
This will test your nerve.
Let it.
All who cannot fight
will be barricaded inside.
This is to be our keep.
Our fallback point.
Take heart. All of you.
I have seen smaller
armies defeat greater foes.
Soon, the sun will set.
Do your part, and I swear to
you, you shall see it rise again.
- Do you believe it?
- Aye.
- Aye!
To your positions.
What about me?
Tavern.
Tavern's for wounded and
children. I can fight.
I know you can.
Which is why I need you in there,
protecting those who cannot.
Come.
Remember when I was little...
When I used to have bad dreams?
I remember.
You remember what you used to say?
When you would hold me in the dark?
Would you say it to me now?
"In the end, this shadow is
but a small and passing thing.
There is light and high beauty
forever beyond its reach.
Find the light...
And the shadow will not find you."
Farewell, Mother.
Are you ready?
No. Are you?
The alfirin seeds...
It is a tradition among Elves.
Before the battle begins, plant one.
New life, in defiance of death?
It is believed that one of the Valar
watches over growing things...
And those who tend them.
The rest...
we shall plant after the battle is over.
In a new garden.
You and I.
And Theo.
Together.
Promise me.
They're here.
Oh, dear...
The bleeding fools missed us.
Come on!
They're headed for the tavern.
- Fight for the Southlands!
The land is ours!
More than a bit brave,
Elf. More than a bit.
Bronwyn.
We were fighting our own.
Thought we'd take 'em in for nothin'?
Had to pay the toll...
And now, all of you will.
Tredwill!
Mother!
Everyone, to the keep!
Go! Go!
Into the tavern!
The tavern!
All of you!
Go!
The table!
Hurry!
Mother. Mother.
Help him first.
No.
We will help you.
Mother.
Theo...
You'll have to stem the bleeding.
I... I don't think I...
Either you're gonna do this or
I'm gonna die. Do you understand?
Theo.
Mother, prepare yourself.
I am sorry.
Put pressure on the wound.
Burn...
She's cold. She's lost too much blood.
No. No. No.
She's saying "burn."
The alfirin seeds. We have
to seal the wound with fire.
Bring me some burning wood. Hurry!
Now.
Now this side.
Go on.
That's enough.
Bronwyn?
- Mother?
- Bronwyn?
Wake up! Mother!
Nampat!
- Kick 'em in the back!
- Nampat!
Nampat!
Sit down!
What I seek.
Give it to me.
Let them go.
I will consider it.
Why sacrifice their lives
for such a little thing?
The woman next.
No!
- Wait!
- Theo!
It's under here.
No.
Theo!
I'm sorry.
Waldreg, I have a task for you.
They all must die.
Ontamo!
Go.
Hyah!
Father!
- I'm all right.
- I thought you...
I'm all right, Isil.
Soldier.
Their commander?
The item he possesses...
He must not escape with it.
Who is that?
Commander of the Northern Armies.
Galadriel.
Noro lim!
Go!
You remember me?
No.
Stop!
We need him alive.
I need him alive.
You don't know what he did.
Did I cause someone you love pain?
A woman?
Perhaps a child?
Eat your tongue.
Halbrand, put it down.
One cannot satisfy thirst
by drinking sea water.
So, what do you think?
I like the mountains.
You're about to get
a closer look at them.
Commander Galadriel's
putting together a company
to track down the Orcs that escaped,
and I managed to wheedle
the pair of us a spot.
What about Ontamo?
I think I might stay here for
a while. Lend these folk a hand.
- Seen enough battle for a week?
- More like a whole lifetime.
This company, when's it set out?
Don't know for certain. Not
till she's done with him.
When I was a child, I heard
stories of Elves taken by Morgoth.
Tortured. Twisted.
Made into a new and ruined form of life.
You are one of them, are you not?
The Moriondor.
The Sons of the Dark.
The first Orcs.
Uruk.
We prefer "Uruk."
Even Moriondor take
orders from a master.
And I seek yours.
Where is he?
Where is Sauron?
Perhaps we should bring our
prisoners into the sunlight.
After Morgoth's defeat,
the one you call Sauron...
Devoted himself to healing Middle-earth,
bringing its ruined lands
together in perfect order.
He sought to craft a power
not of the flesh...
But over flesh.
A power of the Unseen World.
He bid as many as he could
to follow him far north.
But try as he might...
Something was missing.
A shadow of dark knowledge
that kept itself hidden, even from him.
No matter how much blood
he spilt in its pursuit.
Mmm. For my part...
I sacrificed enough of my
children for his aspirations.
I split him open.
I killed Sauron.
I do not believe you.
You cannot believe an Uruk could do that
which your entire army could not.
I cannot believe that you
are this army's only master.
My children have no master.
They are not children, they are slaves.
But each one has a name.
A heart.
- A heart created by Morgoth.
- We are creations of The One,
Master of the Secret
Fire, the same as you.
As worthy of the breath of life,
and just as worthy of a home.
Soon...
This land will be ours.
Then, you will understand.
No.
Your kind was a mistake.
Made in mockery.
And even if it takes me all of this Age,
I vow to eradicate
every last one of you.
But you shall be kept alive,
so that one day,
before I drive my dagger
into your poisoned heart,
I will whisper in your piked ear
that all your offspring are dead
and the scourge of
your kind ends with you.
It would seem I'm not the only Elf alive
who has been transformed by darkness.
Perhaps your search
for Morgoth's successor
should have ended in your own mirror.
Perhaps I shall begin by
killing you, you slavering Orc.
Galadriel.
Uruk.
Who are you?
Thank you...
For pulling me back.
Was you, pulled me back first.
Whatever it was he did to you,
and whatever it was you did...
Be free of it.
I never believed I could be...
Until today.
Fighting at your side, I...
I felt...
If I could just hold on to that feeling,
keep it with me always,
bind it to my very being, then I...
I felt it, too.
Lord Halbrand.
The Queen Regent wishes to see you.
Queen Regent.
What I owe you... My people
are alive because of you.
As I understand it, they're
alive because of you.
A burden I never sought to take up.
Few of the finest leaders do.
But if you would like
some relief in carrying it,
I may be able to help.
You called for me, Your Majesty?
Bronwyn...
This is Lord Halbrand.
Bronwyn.
Is it true? Are you the
king we were promised?
Yes.
All hail!
All hail to the true
King of the Southlands!
The men of these lands have
awaited this moment a long time.
Not nearly so long as the Elves.
Do not torment yourself.
Many might have done
the same in your place.
You don't understand.
It's not just guilt I feel.
It's loss.
Loss?
When it was in my hands,
I felt...
Powerful.
Then rid yourself of it.
Once and for all.
How?
Give it to Númenor.
To toss into the sea
on their voyage home.
Easy. Berek, easy.
It's just a scratch. You're okay.
Hey, hey, hey. Berek.
Careful.
Athae...
no ídhui hí.
How did you do that?
It's not his pain
that's bothering him...
But that of his rider.
I'm not in pain.
When a horse of Westernesse
rides into battle,
he forms an unbreakable bond
with the soldier he bears.
In time, they become as one.
Even knowing the innermost
feelings of each other's heart.
- You know his feelings?
- No.
He knows yours.
Where did you learn all this?
From your mother.
Think you could teach me?
Udûn...
Udûn. Udûn.
Take shelter!
The Queen!
Berek!
Valandil!
Over the wall!
- Theo!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.MY-SUBS.com --